Anirudhan J. Rajagopalan

linkedin.com/in/rajegannathan github.com/rajegannathan

Summary

Software Engineer with around 5 years of experience. Currently pursuing Masters in Computer Science at New York University. Diversified skills include Full stack Web application development, Deep Learning, DBA, and System Administration. Adept at researching and finding the right and easy way to build software.

Education

Master of Science, Computer Science

Dec 2016

Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, New York University.

CGPA 3.75/4.0

Course List: Deep Learning, GPU — Architecture & Programming, Computational Machine Learning, Foundational Machine Learning, Web Search Engine, Realtime & Big data analysis.

Bachelor of Technology, Information Technology

May 2010

Government College of Technology, Coimbatore

CGPA 8.01/10.0

Academic Projects

2015 - 2016

- Used Convolutional clustering with unlabeled data to improve classification accuracy on STL-10.
- Used LSTM to train a language model on word level Penn Tree Bank dataset. (torch)
- Built a feature based reviews extractor for Amazon reviews. (java, python)
- Used VLAD feature representation for classifying EEG signals for Grasp & Lift problem.
- Classifying Liver & Kidney cancer using unbalanced protein expression data. Accuracy 97%.
- Exploratory correlation analysis between NYC Taxi ridership and public events.

Work Experience

Around 5 years

Data Science Intern

Eyenuk Inc, Los Angeles, CA.

Jun 2016 — Aug 2016

- Explored the classification of Diabetic Retinopathy with Residual Networks against VGG model.
- Setup the scalable production AWS deployment using VPC, Route 53, ELB, ACM, and RDS.

Full-stack Software Consultant

Bangalore, India

May 2013 — Jan 2015

Quirl by Canvera Digital Technologies

Jan 2014 — Sep 2014

- Performance Optimizations Load time: ~10 sec \rightarrow 1 sec. Asset size: ~1.5Mb \rightarrow ~600Kb.
- Built a rails like asset pipeline using Grunt and made the application production ready.
- Setup the application architecture & development process. Mentored the development team.

f1circle.com

May 2013 — Nov 2013

- Built the complete application from scratch. (ROR, Angularjs, Memcached, Redis)
- Built Information extraction engine. It extracts name, place, & price info from user's posts.

Other projects

- Implemented the common sign-on page, branding workflows and modal framework for Vera.
- Built Urblotter (app.urblotter.com) a betting website for FIFA 2014. (ROR, Angularjs).

Software Enginneer

Insideview Inc, India

Oct 2011 — May 2013

- Developed in-product notification framework using **Drools framework** & **Lucene indexes**.
- Built the Activitystream security framework using AWS Simpledb and custom eventbus.
- Built an award winning Company recommendation engine in Insideview Hackaton 2012. (Java)

Software Engineer

United Online Inc, India

Jul 2010 — Sep 2011

• Built a RPC framework for spam filtering. Automated day-to-day tasks using Perl scripts.